invisiblechildren.com 2019-12-24

# Privacy Policy | Invisible Children

Your privacy is important to us. To better protect your privacy, we provide this notice explaining our information collection, storing, and sharing practices. This notice applies to all information collected by or submitted to Invisible Children. Please note that this policy is subject to change. 

The information we collect and how we collect it 

Our website uses cookies and Google Analytics to collect information about user activity on our website. Most pages on our website can be visited without revealing any personal information. 

On some pages, you can make requests to receive email updates, make donations, and register to receive information about political advocacy initiatives. On these pages, you can choose to share the following types of information: 

  * Name
  * Employer Name
  * Address
  * Email Address
  * Phone/Number
  * Credit/Debit Card Information
  * Age
  * Date of Birth (DOB)

Donations to Invisible Children are processed through a third party processor called Classy. You can review Classy’s privacy policy [here](https://www.classy.org/terms/privacy/). Our privacy policy does not necessarily apply to Classy or to other third-party pages or applications hosted or operated by other organizations. 

What are cookies and Google Analytics? 

A cookie is a small text file that our site may place on your computer as a tool to remember your preferences. You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser. 

Google Analytics transmits website traffic data to Google servers and does not identify individual users or associate your IP address with any other data held by Google. We use reports provided by Google Analytics to help us understand website traffic. You can read about the Google Analytics cookie usage [here](https://developers.google.com/analytics/devguides/collection/analyticsjs/cookie-usage). You can opt out of Google Analytics if you disable or refuse the cookie, disable JavaScript, or use the opt-out service provided by Google. 

How we use the information 

We collect aggregate use information, such as the number of hits per page, for internal and marketing use only; we will never provide your personally identifying information to the public. 

We use the information you provide about yourself when making a donation to complete that donation and to communicate with you about your donation and its impact. We do not share this information with outside parties except to the extent necessary to process your donation. You can unsubscribe from communication about the impact of your donation at any time. 

When you email Invisible Children or submit a request via the form on our Contact Page, we use return email addresses to answer the email we receive. Such addresses are not used for any other purpose and are not shared with outside parties unless you provide explicit permission to do so. 

Finally, we never use or share the personally identifiable information provided to us in ways unrelated to the ones described above without your explicit consent. 

Our commitment to data security 

To prevent unauthorized access, maintain data accuracy, and ensure the correct use of information, we have put in place appropriate physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online. 

Your rights over your personal information 

Any personal data collected or stored by Invisible Children is yours. We respect your rights to the following: 

  * To be informed of how your data is processed
  * To rectify inaccuracies in your data
  * To instruct us to delete your data
  * To restrict our processing of your data at any time, including unsubscribing from email lists

If you wish to exercise any of these rights you can do so by contacting us [here](https://invisiblechildren.com/contact-us/). You can unsubscribe from email lists by clicking on the unsubscribe link at the bottom of any email or by contacting us directly.
